[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Very good.
جيد جدًا.
We've now seen the simple gradient ascent algorithm for logistic regression.
لقد تعرفنا على خوارزمية الصعود التدريجي البسيط للانحدار اللوجستي.
How we update the parameters, how we implement it and
كيف نقوم بتحديث المتغيرات، وكيف ننفذها
we talked a little bit about how to set that step size parameter
وتحدثنا قليلاً عن كيفية تعيين متغير من خطوة واحدة
[INAUDIBLE] parameter and what impact it has on the progress of our algorithm.
أو بمعنى آخر أفضل متغير من خطوة واحدة وتأثيره على تقدم خوارزميتنا.
Now I'm going to take a little bit of time to show you how to derive the derivative
الآن سأستغرق بعض الوقت لعرض كيفية اشتقاق مشتق
of the likelihood function for logistic regression, how that gradient is computed.
دالة الاحتمال للانحدار اللوجستي، وكيفية حساب هذا التدرج.
The material we're going to talk about here is quite mathematical.
المادة التي سنتحدث عنها هنا رياضية إلى حد بعيد.
This is really PhD level material and it can be a little
فهي مادة بمستوى الدكتوراه وقد تكون
annoying but for some folks, it might be exciting to go through every detail.
مزعجة بالنسبة لبعض الناس، وقد تكون شيقة حيث توفر التفاصيل الدقيقة.
For others, this could be something that you skip and it doesn't change anything.
بالنسبة للآخرين، يمكن تخطي ذلك دون التأثير على أي شيء.
Up to you, you're warned but it's there for when you want to learn more about it.
الأمر متروك لك، لقد تم تحذيرك، والفيديو موجود عندما تريد معرفة المزيد.
We're going to jump in to deriving the gradient for
سنقوم ننتقل إلى اشتقاق التدرج
the likelihood function for logistic regression.
لدالة احتمالية الانحدار اللوجستي.
Again, PhD level material.
مرة أخرى، المادة بمستوى الدكتوراه.
Here we go.
لنتابع.
As we said, our goal is to pick the coefficients w to maximize
كما قلنا، هدفنا هو اختيار معاملات w لتعظيم
the likelihood function and
دالة الاحتمالية
that is the product of our data points are the probability of yi given xi and w.
وهو نتاج نقاط البيانات الخاصة بنا واحتمالية yi مع المعطيات xi و w.
Now, it turns out that all the math that we need
الآن، تبين أن كل الرياضيات التي نحتاجها
to do becomes quite a lot simpler if you take the log of that likelihood function.
تصبح أكثر بساطة إذا أخذت لوغاريتم الدالة الاحتمالية.
I'm going to call that ll(w) and this is the natural log ln,
وسأطلق عليه ll (w) وهذا هو السجل الطبيعي ln،
natural log of that product.
لوغاريتم طبيعي لهذه النتيجة.
Now, turns out for most of machine learning, especially for stuff,
الآن، يتضح لمعظم التعلم الآلي، وخاصة المفاهيم الاحتمالية،
you often take the log, and it usually makes your math a lot simpler.
غالبا ما تأخذ اللوغاريتم، فهو يجعل الرياضيات أكثر بساطة.
Logs are your friends.
فاللوغاريتمات توفر العون.
Let me do kind of a quick review of the log, natural log function.
اسمحوا لي أن أفعل نوعًا من المراجعة السريعة للوغاريتم، دالة اللوغاريتم الطبيعي.
Log lm and raise the function here that I am showing.
ln وهي الدالة التي أعرضها هنا.
You might have on the x-axis some value z,
قد يكون لديك على محور x بعض القيمة z،
on the y-axis this is what the log of z looks like and
على y-axis هذا هو ما يبدو سجل z
you see that it's something that actually at zero would be minus infinity.
ترى أنه في الواقع سيكون الصفر عند اللانهاية السالبة.
It grows quickly at first and then kind of much, much,
ينمو بسرعة في البداية ثم يتباطأ كثيرًا
much slower later but this is what the log does.
في وقت لاحق فهذا ما يفعله اللوغاريتم.
The reason that it's useful is that the big product that we had
والسبب في أنه مفيد هو أن النتيجة الكبيرة التي لدينا
actually becomes a sum.
تصبح في الواقع المجموع.
In general, if you have the log of a times b that is equal to the log a plus log b.
بشكل عام، إذا كان لديك لوغاريتم a في b، فهذا يساوي لوغاريتم a زائد لوغاريتم b.
Similarly, if you have the log of a over b,
وبالمثل، إذا كان لديك لوغاريتم a على b،
that is the log of a minus the log of b.
فهو لوغاريتم a ناقص لوغاريتم b.
Here's a side note.
ملاحظة جانبية.
I remember, in high school, I think, I learned about log function, and
أتذكر، في المدرسة الثانوية، أعتقد، تعلمت الدالة اللوغاريتمية،
that the log of a times b is log a plus log b and I thought my god,
وأن لوغاريتم a في b هو لوغاريتم a زائد لوغاريتم b،
this is the most useless thing I've ever seen.
وكنت أعتقد أن هذا لا فائدة منه.
Why are they spending time teaching it?
لماذا يضيعون الوقت في تدريسه؟
It really took about six years before I actually saw it was useful for something.
لقد استغرق الأمر بالفعل حوالي ست سنوات قبل أن أرى بالفعل أنه مفيد لشيء ما.
It's actually extremely useful for machine learning, a funny side note.
فهو مفيد للغاية للتعلم الآلي، ملاحظة جانبية فكاهية.
But anyway, a log has some very interesting properties.
ولكن على أي حال، يحتوي اللوغاريتم على بعض الخصائص الهامة.
The other property it has is that you take a function F and
الخاصية الأخرى الذي يملكها هو أنه في حالة التعامل مع الدالة F
you compute it's maximum, taking the log doesn't change anything.
وحساب الحد الأقصى، لا يقوم اللوغاريتم بتغيير أي شيء.
If you don't note W hat here to be,
إذا لم تلاحظ وجود W hat هنا،
we're going to call it the arg
سوف نسميها max arg
max over w of f(w) and
على w للدالة f(w)
this notation here just means
هذا الترميز هنا يعني فقط
the w that makes f(w) largest.
w الذي يجعل f (w) أكبر.
And if you were to take the log of that function,
وإذا كنا سنأخذ لوغاريتم الدالة،
let's call W hat underscore ln to be
دعنا ندعوه W hat تسطير سفلي ln ليكون
the thing that maximizes the log of f(w).
الشيء الذي يزيد من لوغاريتم f(w).
So w hat ln =
w hat ln =
arg max over w of
arg max على w
the log (f(w))
للوغاريتم (f(w
because log is what's called the positive monotonic function.
ولأن اللوغاريتم يسمى بالدالة الرتيبة الإيجابية.
This doesn't change the optimum, this transformation.
هذا لا يغير من المستوى الأمثل، أو هذا التحول.
It turns out that w hat is going to be equal to w hat ln.
اتضح أن w hat سوف يكون مساويًا ل w hat ln.
What we did in the previous slide, we just take the log of the likelihood function,
ما فعلناه في الشريحة السابقة، نحن فقط نأخذ لوغاريتم الدالة الاحتمالية،
still keeps the optimum exactly at the same place.
لا يزال يحتفظ بالمستوى الأمثل بالضبط في نفس المكان.
And it's going to make your math quite a bit easier.
وسوف يجعل المعادلات الرياضية أكثر سهولة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]